A Guide to the Norfleet Family Papers, 1845-1977
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Norfleet Family Papers, 1845-1977
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
8809-i
This collection consists of 46 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library by Mrs. Fillmore Norfleet of Charlottesville, Virginia on September 2, 1988.
Scope and Content Information
This collection of 46 items, ca. 1845-1977, consists of correspondence, photographs, printed material, and a scrapbook. The material pertains to John Powell and, also, to the Norfleet, Scott, and related families.
Material concerning John Powell includes letters from him and his wife, Louise Burleigh, to their employees, John and Lydia Banks; photographs, and printed material. The letters are job-related and include recommendations. There are two photographs of John Powell, one inscribed "To Grace from her friend John Powell," presented to Grace (Mrs. Walter Scott) Copeland. Printed material includes a musical score, "Soldier, Soldier," John Powell Foundation brochures, and obituaries for both John and Louise (Burleigh) Powell.
Material pertaining to the Baker, Norfleet, Riddick, Scott, and related families include 19 photographs (chiefly cased ambrotypes and daguerreotypes) as well as miscellaneous and printed material. There is an unsigned autograph note on his personal calling card, January 31, 1918, from Theodore Roosevelt to Mr. and Mrs. W. S. Copeland. There is also a printed flyer about Jo Lane Stern, a Confederate soldier, inscribed on its backing, "For my good old friend Copeland with best wishes. Jo Lane Stern." In addition, there are programs and brochures, 1977, pertaining to Joe Layton's production of Paul Green's "The Lost Colony," in Manteo, North Carolina. Material about the Richmond Bicentennial Celebration includes the official magazine and program, and a play, "The Cavalcade of the Cavaliers" by Jan Isbelle Fortune. There is also a scrapbook of newspaper clippings, 1939-1941, on Massanutten Academy, Woodstock, Virginia.
Contents List
- John Powell Papers
  - Letters from John and Louise Burleigh Powell to John and Lydia Banks 1944-1960
  - Photographs of John Powell n.d.
  - Printed Material re John and Louise Burleigh Powell 1936-1963
- Family Papers
  - Micellaneous 1918,1977
  - Photographs of Virginia families n.d.
  - Richmond Bicentennial Celebration featuring "Cavalcade of the Cavaliers" 1937
  - Scrapbook of newpaper clippings 1939-1941
    re Massanutten Academy
- Cased Photographs
  - David Baker of Richmond (left); Rebecca Kelly Baker of Richmond (right), Daguerreotypes
  - Dinah Shelton Joynes, Mrs. Healey Joynes, Daguerreotype
  - Hugh Lindsay of County Down, Ireland, officer on the Merrimac, Ambrotype
  - Elisha and Sarah Elizabeth Riddick Norfleet, his second wife, Ambrotype
  - Hamlin Lassiter Norfleet, as a boy, Ambrotype
  - Hamlin Lassiter Norfleet, as a young man, Ambrotype
  - Great Grandmother Norfleet, Tintype (no case)
  - Emma Baker Scott, Mrs. William H. Scott of Richmond, Daguerreotype
  - Emma Baker Scott, Mrs. William H. Scott of Richmond, Ambrotype
  - Mary Eliza Shelton Scott, Mrs. Robert Taylor Scott (later Mrs. Hugh Lindsay), and her daughter, Elizabeth Moseley Scott (later Mrs. Judson Cunningham), of Richmond, Ambrotype
  - Robert Taylor Scott of Portsmouth, Daguerreotype
  - William H. and Emma Baker Scott of Richmond, Ambrotype
  - Unknown female, Ambrotype
  - Unknown male, Ambrotype
  - Unknown male, Daguerreotype
  - Unknown male, Daguerreotype
  - Unknown child, Ambrotype
  - Jethro Riddick, Photo (no case)
  - Elizabeth Vaughan Riddick, Photo (no case)